## NAVRATAN GUPTA

SYSTEM ENGINEER

Download PDF

navratan.gupta04@gmail.com

+91 99010 80916

Imagination is my greatest strength. It helps in making knowledge applicable for solving problems. Knowledge is limited. Imagination encircles the world.

Skills

**Operating Systems** 

Unix based OS (SLES/RHEL/DEBIAN), Windows 7/8/10 Programming Languages

Python3, Shell Scripting, C++

RDBMS

Oracle SQL, PL/SQL

Tools

uDeploy, git, Jenkins, Jira, Docker, Ansible Miscellaneous

github/bitbucket, Data structures & Algorithms

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

PROFESSIONAL I am currently working with TATA Consultancy Services as a System engineer.

3+ years of experience on Continuous Deployment technology using IBM UrbanCode Deploy.

I have  ${\bf Automated}$  multiple complex tasks to help save effort and time.

Awarded with  $\bf Technical\ Excellence\ Award$  by TCS.

Hands on experience with C++.

Hands on SDLC tools i.e. bitbucket/stash, github, Confluence, Jira & Jfrog Artifactory

Experience

Tata Consulatancy Services

Mar 2017 - Present

System Engineer

**Facilitate the deployment automation** on testing & production environments using IBM UrbanCode Deploy.

Integrating uDeploy with Teamcity, ServiceNow, Jenkins and middleware platforms.

Vigilant **service monitoring** and watchful to any production security violations on uDeploy platform.

 $\textbf{Testing of new functionalities} \ \text{of uDeploy tool, pre-} \ \text{and post-release}.$ 

Automating complex and time inefficient tasks for smooth and efficient service delivery.

Active participation in deployment activities.

Bug fixing, resolving on-fly issues, roles and access level managements.

Active participation in mandates like server upgrades & patches, Server & Application disaster recovery activity and business continuity test.

Collaboration on various knowledge articles on team collaboration tool i.e. Confluence.

Working on agents connectivity, SSH, WinsSCP.

Working on Jira, Bitbucket, Github and Artifactory repository.

1 of 2 21/04/20, 1:24 am

Tata Consulatancy Services

Jan 2017 - Mar 2017

Assistant System Engineer - Trainee

Initial Learning Program (ILP) in TCS, Guwahati. Trained on Oracle, SQL and C++ Technology.

Education

Nagpur University - Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Electronics and Communication -7.49 CGPA

2012 - 2016

Central Board of Secondary Education

Senior Secondary School Examination, PCM -80.3%

2010 - 2012

Central Board of Secondary Education

Secondary School Examination — 8.8 CGPA

2010

Navratan Gupta — <a href="mailto:navratan.guptao4@gmail.com">navratan.guptao4@gmail.com</a> — +91 99010 80916

<u>LinkedIn</u> Github

2 of 2 21/04/20, 1:24 am